RAHUL SINGH

i.am.rahul@live.com | (778) 636-2496 | Delta, BC

Expert Communicator | Efficient | Detail Oriented

Summary
Software Quality Assurance Analyst with a background in DevOps, Databases, and programming. Software development experience from the University of British Columbia and the British Columbia Institute of Technology. Have previously developed apps for sponsors and have implemented a software pipeline with Jenkins and Microsoft Azure. Competencies include:
♦ Making and maintaining Cloud Infrastructure with Azure and AWS
 Developing applications for industry sponsors, including documentation
♦ Managing databases with MySQL and business analysis with Excel and DAX
JOB RELATED Experience
Developer (Industry Projects) BCIT: Vancouver, BC January 2022—June 2023
 Communicated with Clients to gather project requirements, expectations, deadlines, and project management tools
♦ Managed project development with technologies such as Git, Trello, Slack, Agile, Teams
♦ Built 5+ mock applications to demonstrate potential solutions for client requests
♦ Implemented a continuous integration pipeline with customized cloud infrastructure from Microsoft Azure
♦ Managed a picture database on AWS for a x-ray application
Education
Computer Information Technology Diploma, British Columbia Institute of Technology, Vancouver, Canada 2023
 ◆ Business Analysis ◆ Database Admin ◆ DevOps
Bachelors in Cognitive Systems, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, Canada
◆ Computer Science ◆ Research Methods ◆ Algorithms
Certifications

Power BI Data Analyst Associate, Microsoft Certified: Data Analyst Associate

Page 1 of 2

2024

RAHUL SINGH

i.am.rahul@live.com | (778) 636-2496 | Delta, BC

Expert Communicator | Efficient | Detail Oriented

Other Experience

Digital Image Technician (Freelance)

Present

Enkaur Productions: Vancouver

- Managed video and audio files for various projects including TV Series, documentaries and online content
- Coordinated transfer of files on physical media and managed logistics to coordinate between as many as 5 post-production departments
- Liaised with department heads to ensure smooth delivery to platforms
- Assisted lead editor in organizing footage, syncing footage, uploading multiple cuts for review on frame.io and other duties as required by the editor

Research Assistant (Volunteer)

May 2018—May 2019

Centre for Gambling Research: Vancouver, BC

- Administered gambling research experiments to collect data on skin conductance and grip strength
- Analyzed performance across multiple participants and sessions to answer research questions
- Submitted an oral presentation and written report summarizing the research and results

Stock Person

November 2012—April 2015

Hewer Home Hardware: Vancouver, BC

- Communicated product knowledge to customers
- Collaborated with customers to narrow in on their problems and suggest solutions
- Ensured merchandise is stocked and available to be purchased by customers
- Unloaded and received inventory and prepared items to be shelved

Technical Competencies

-

- Microsoft Azure
- ♦ MySQL

♦ Python

Power BI

♦ AWS

Automated Testing

Interests

•

Data Science, board games, Contemporary literature, music, volunteering